You're in line at the grocery /ˈɡrəʊsərɪ/ store when, uh oh,
someone sneezes /sniːz 打喷嚏/ on you.
The cold virus is sucked inside your lungs
and lands on a cell on your airway lining.
Every living thing on Earth is made of cells,
from the smallest one-celled bacteria /bækˈtɪərɪə 细菌/
to the giant blue whale to you.
Each cell in your body is surrounded by a cell membrane /ˈmɛmbreɪn 膜/,
a thick flexible layer made of fats and proteins,
that surrounds and protects the inner components /kəmˈpəʊnənt/.
It's semipermeable /semi'pə:miəbl 半透的/,
meaning that it lets some thing pass in and out
but blocks others.
The cell membrane /ˈmɛmbreɪn 膜/ is covered with tiny projections /prəˈdʒɛkʃən 突出 投射/.
They all have functions,
like helping cells adhere /ədˈhɪə 黏附/ to their neighbors
or binding to nutrients /ˈnjuːtrɪənt 营养品/ the cell will need.
Animal and plant cells have cell membranes.
Only plant cells have a cell wall,
which is made of rigid /ˈrɪdʒɪd 坚硬的/ cellulose /ˈsɛljʊˌləʊz 纤维素/ that gives the plant structure.
The virus cell that was sneezed into your lungs is sneaky /ˈsniːkɪ 鬼鬼祟祟的/.
Pretending /prɪˈtɛnd 伪装/ to be a friend,
it attaches to a projection on the cell membrane,
and the cell brings it through the cell membrane and inside.
When the virus gets through,
the cell recognizes its mistake.
An enemy is inside!
Special enzymes /ˈenzaɪm 酶/ arrive at the scene
and chop the virus to pieces.
They then send one of the pieces back
through the cell membrane,
where the cell displays it to warn neighboring cells
about the invader.
A nearby cell sees the warning
and immediately goes into action.
It needs to make antibodies /ˈæntɪˌbɒdɪ 抗体/,
proteins that will attack and kill
the invading virus.
This process starts in the nucleus /ˈnjuːklɪəs 细胞核/.
The nucleus contains our DNA,
the blueprint that tells our cells how to make everything
our bodies need to function.
A certain section of our DNA contains instructions
that tell our cells how to make antibodies.
Enzymes /ˈenzaɪm 酶/ in the nucleus /ˈnjuːklɪəs 细胞核/ find the right section of DNA,
then create a copy of these instructions,
called messenger RNA.
The messenger RNA leaves the nucleus to carry out its orders.
The messenger RNA travels to a ribosome /ˈraɪbəˌsəʊm 核糖体/.
There can be as many as 10 million ribosomes /ˈraɪbəˌsəʊm 核糖体/
in a human cell,
all studded /stʌd 饰钉 布满/ along a ribbon/ˈrɪbən 缎带/-like structure
called the endoplasmic /ˌendəʊˈplæzmɪk 内质的/ reticulum /riˈtikjuləm 网状组织/.
This ribosome /ˈraɪbəˌsəʊm 核糖体/ reads the instructions from the nucleus.
It takes amino /əˈmaɪnəʊ 氨基的/ acids /ˈæsɪd 酸/ and links them together one by one
creating an antibody protein that will go fight the virus.
But before it can do that,
the antibody needs to leave the cell.
The antibody heads to the golgi /ɡɔ:ldʒi 高尔基体/ apparatus /ˌæpəˈreɪtəs 仪器 机构/.
Here, it's packed up for delivery outside the cell.
Enclosed in a bubble made of the same material as the cell membrane,
the golgi apparatus also gives the antibody directions,
telling it how to get to the edge of the cell.
When it gets there,
the bubble surrounding the antibody fuses /fjuːz 熔化/ to the cell membrane.
The cell ejects /ɪˈdʒɛkt 驱逐 弹射出/ the antibody,
and it heads out to track /træk 跟踪/ down the virus.
The leftover /ˈleftˌəʊvə 剩余的/ bubble will be broken down
by the cell's lysosomes /ˈlaɪsəˌsəʊm 溶酶体/
and its pieces recycled over and over again.
Where did the cell get the energy to do all this?
That's the roll of the mitochondria /ˌmaɪtəʊˈkɒndrɪə 线粒体/.
To make energy, the mitochondria /ˌmaɪtəʊˈkɒndrɪə 线粒体/ takes oxygen,
this is the only reason we breathe /briːð 呼吸/ it,
and adds electrons /ɪˈlɛktrɒn 电子/ from the food we eat
to make water molecules /ˈmɒlɪˌkjuːl 分子/.
That process also creates a high energy molecule /ˈmɒlɪˌkjuːl 分子/,
called ATP which the cell uses to power all of its parts.
Plant cells make energy a different way.
They have chloroplasts /ˈklɔːrəʊˌplæst 叶绿体/
that combine carbon dioxide /daɪˈɒksaɪd 二氧化物/ and water
with light energy from the sun
to create oxygen and sugar,
a form of chemical energy.
All the parts of a cell have to work together
to keep things running smoothly,
and all the cells of your body have to work together
to keep you running smoothly.
That's a whole lot of cells.
Scientists think there are about 37 trillion of them.